summer moon is one of my favorite go-to
coffee shops in Temple its location is
super convenient located off of West
Adams in the Trinity Plaza just minutes
from Baylor Scot and white campus and
about 3 minutes from my office front
door admittingly I am a Starbucks junkie
don't hate me so this is a really great
alternative when I'm looking for a sweet
treat this locally owned Temple Coffee
Shop is known for Unique Oak roasted
coffee and signature sweet cream
moonmilk now I love spending time with
clients here because the atmosphere is
so cute super inviting and the coffee is
fantastic um I actually really love
their pastries too all of their pastries
I think are locally sourced and made um
as you can see here I had a cream cheese
cinnamon roll which they warmed up for
me it was perfect and they also have
these little poptarts I haven't tried
them but I've heard wonderful things
about them if you have let me know your
thoughts they also have a drive-thru
Order ahead and an app which is super
convenient on the go the last time I
stopped in I saw my sweet little friend
Grace she also cuts my kids hair at
Beautiful Salon in belon yes it said
just like that but I love this community
and running into some of my favorite
people here with MacKenzie Fleming she's
one of the owners it's going to tell us
a little bit about summer Moon and how
it got started so McKenzie tell us a
little bit about uh summer Moon Yeah so
summer moon is a franchise out of Austin
we was founded in 2002 um what's really
cool about summer moon is our coffee is
what's called Oak roasted coffee and all
of our beans here in the store and
across every summer Moon across America
is roasted locally in Austin over a live
flame and so if you go on our website
summer mo.com you can actually see the
roasting process and what's really cool
is it takes all that bitterness out of
coffee it's unlike any roasting process
you're going to find it's an 18th
century roaster so it's very old um and
now they have four Roasters just from
growing and expanding so much and of
course our moon milk which is our
signature sweet cream is just so dreamy
and so good it's so good yeah and so it
was founded in 2002 and we franchised
with uh summer Moon back in
2021 or 2020 right at the peak in the
height of copen and what actually
started it is we went down to see my
sister who lived in Austin at the time
with my first daughter and she ended up
getting an ear infection and so we were
up all night long did not firsttime
parents did not know what was going on
and why she wasn't sleeping and the next
morning I remember telling my sister
McKenna who's also one of the owners um
I want some really good coffee like I
don't really want Starbucks I don't I
was a big Starbucks drinker but I didn't
want that I'm in Austin like I want
something that is aw coffee right and um
she goes have you ever heard a summer
Moon and I said no and so we went that
morning and four cups
later um we headed home and we're on our
it's you know PE of hide of Co my
husband's in the medical field and so
he's he was home for 6 7 months
um so we were on our what fifth walk of
the day cuz there was nothing else to do
and he's like I wonder if summer Moon
franchises like if it's a franchise
opportunity and long story short he
called the number on the website and we
had a some sit Downs with the family the
founders and we clicked and had um
really good conversations and our values
line with theirs very well and so um
yeah long story short now we're here two
locations later weren't you a um a food
truck yes so we still have our trailer
in belon it's over on uh Sparta Road it
is moving at the end of this year um
that is something that has not quite
been announced yet we don't know where
we're moving to I don't have any
information on that our the the land was
sold to a different company um just
better business and I totally understand
that and so we do have to move shortly
but the trailer was our first location
and then the temple location opened
about a year and a half after that um
we're coming up on our 2-year
anniversary here and so now yeah that's
about it I love it so I'm currently
drinking the mocha Moon um I'm an iced
coffee girl I'd love to hear if you're
an iced coffee drinker a hot coffee
drinker comment below but I often get
the iced Blue Moon can you tell what the
the ice blue moon yeah so our Blue Moon
is our lavender latte it comes with moon
milk skim milk and lavender um and of
course OK roasted espresso and it's
built as a quarter moon so it's a little
bit on the lower sweetness level most of
our drinks are built as a half moon
unless you want something different
unless you specify different um but the
Blue Moon is definitely a favorite I
love it iced that's my go-to in the
summer is a iced Blue Moon yep so super
like she said super dreamy super it's
got that floral HT to it and when I'm
filling chocy the mil ice smoka Moon and
then explain a little bit about the
corners Half Moon thek how that works
yeah so what's cool about summer moon is
you have the opportunity for all of our
drinks to be very custom um our moon
milk is what makes the sweet you can we
do offer drinks that are don't have Moon
milk in it like a regular Latt tap lots
of people don't think we offer that but
we do oh good um but the moon milk is
what makes it sweet sweet it's our sweet
cream right so the more you add to it
the more sweet it's going to get most
people start at a half moon right in the
middle of our sweetness level um and
then a quarter is going to be a little
less sweet we do offer what's called a
whisper Moon which is our kind of off
menu item um but it's a just a splash of
moon milk very very light on the
sweetness level and then you can go all
the way up to a Full Moon which is all
Moon milk and espresso okay and what
would you say so top three most popular
yeah drinks here oh that's such a great
question um our our our Blue Moon is
very popular not very many people offer
a lavender drink right and so that's
going to be really popular um a lot of
people love a good half moon I mean it's
just that staple right but if you had to
ask what the
third I would say our signature like
our limited time offer drinks of all
those the Christmas cookie which is what
I'm drinking oh okay the Christmas
cookie is very popular this time of year
it's a good hot cold both both so good
so it's um it has cinnamon roasted
Hazelnut and gingerbread syrup in it but
it's topped with whipped cream and
sprinkles so it's very festive um and
it's it's so so good okay and what would
you say your best top alternative drink
is for those who don't enjoy coffee yeah
so we offer chai and machas as
well something that a lot of people like
is a strawberry matcha it's I'm not a
huge yeah I'm not I'm not a huge matcha
like person um preferably but some
people get the matcha with moon milk so
matcha Moon and then add strawberry so a
strawberry matcha moon is how you would
say that how you would order that um and
a lot of people seem to like that it's
that sweet with the moon milk but the
earthy flavors right of the matcha and
then um a chai as far as chai go
probably a vanilla chai a lot of people
get just a regular vanilla chai yeah
awesome well those all sounds so good to
me I hope that you stop by summer moon
in Temple Texas and check it out you
won't be
disappointed thank you so much for
having me and for sharing all there to
know about summer Moon Yeah I appreciate
you thank you thank you if you've tried
summer Moon yourself I'd love to hear
what your favorite is drop a comment
below if you're new to my channel don't
forget to subscribe like this video and
hit the Bell icon so you can stay up
toate on all things living in CTX bye
[Music]